Well, how did it go?
You may have run into a few problems, but a problem is just a stepping stone in your learning, which
leads to growth.
Yeah, I know it's quite profound, isn't it?
But that's what it is.
Anyway, let's just get to it.
So we want to change the score by one each time our guy gets a header and our guy is getting a header
when he is touching the ball.
So if you look at the script here, it's basically doing that.
It's sensing if we are touching Ben.
So it works perfectly for our variable change and we don't even need to create a new script.
So let's do this.
If the ball touches Ben, we want to change our variable score by one and change the ball's direction.
So let's check this out.
Clicking play you will see when we get a header it works.
But just before you celebrate too much, see that if we touch the ball from the side.
We get a whole stack of points, and that's one way to cheat in our game.
That's a bit of a hack, so we definitely need to fix that.
And also notice that when we restart the game, our score stays at the same number.
So firstly we can fix our score, not a restarting simply by adding this set variable block to the start
of our script.
And this way each time we start our game, our score is reset to zero.
Our next problem needs a smarter fix.
Because if you look at this code, if Ben is touching the ball, it changes the variable by one and
it keeps doing this until he's not touching the ball.
So even if we are only touching for a second, the score will increase a bunch of times in that second.
So to fix this, add in a wait one second right to the end of the code and we don't even need it to
be that long.
So let's change it maybe to half a second.
Now, if you look at the script, we set our score to zero.
Then if we touch Ben, we change the direction, change our score.
Then we wait for one second, which means that our players can't cheat anymore.
And with that, your scoring is done.
And one quick tip if you double click on the variable, you can make it big like this.
And also you can move it around and put it anywhere on your screen.
Now have some fun with this game and try it out and see how high can you get.
What is your high score?
Have some fun because you are busy creating an absolutely amazing game.